zellepay.com 2019-07-21

# Privacy Policy Zelle

**Privacy Policy _Last Updated:_ May 21, 2019**

Welcome! Thank you for visiting Zelle®.

The _Zelle Network_ (referred to as " _Zelle_ ," "we," "our," or "us") provides a service that enables a convenient way to transfer money between you and others who are enrolled directly with _Zelle_ or enrolled with a financial institution that partners with _Zelle_ (each, a “User”) using aliases, such as email addresses or mobile phone numbers. We refer to financial institutions that have partnered with _Zelle_ as “Network Financial Institutions.”

This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) explains our information privacy practices and the choices you can make about the collection, use, disclosure, and retention of information you submit or we collect through our website [zellepay.com](https://www.zellepay.com/) and/or the Zelle mobile app. We specify in this Privacy Policy when the contents apply to our website or the Zelle mobile app and we use the term “Site” when the contents apply to both. The Site is owned and operated by Early Warning Services, LLC.

To make this Privacy Policy easy to find, we make it available on the [zellepay.com](https://www.zellepay.com/) homepage and in the _Zelle_ mobile app.

### _Contents & Summary_

A list summarizing the contents of this Privacy Policy appears below, followed by the full Privacy Policy. Should there be any discrepancy between the summary and the full Privacy Policy, the language of the full Privacy Policy governs.

  * Scope and Consent

By using the Site, you expressly consent to our collection, use, disclosure, and retention of your personal information and other information as described in this Privacy Policy.

Your use of the website and/or _Zelle_ mobile app is also governed by the User Service Agreement [User Service Agreement](https://zellepay.com/user-service-agreement), the [Just in Time Notice](https://zellepay.com/just-time-notice), and [Terms of Use](https://zellepay.com/terms-use). Do not use the Site if you do not agree to these terms.

  * Information We Collect or Access About You

When you use the Site, we may collect or access the following information:

    * (a) Enrollment and Profile Information: We collect personal information when you enroll in the _Zelle_ mobile app and when you update your profile in the _Zelle_ mobile app.

    * (b) Information about Your Transactions: When you use the _Zelle_ mobile app to send or request money, we collect information about the transaction.

    * (c) Information to Respond to Your Requests: You may give us your personal information when you contact us for assistance and when you sign up for our newsletters and for other communications.

    * (d) Information about Your Friends and Family that You Invite to Join _Zelle_ : If you invite your friends and family to join _Zelle_ or you initiate a money transfer to or from them, you may give us their personal information so we can invite them to use _Zelle_.

    * (e) Information From Other Sources: We may combine information from outside sources to customize your experience on the Site and for security, authentication, and identity verification purposes.

    * (f) Content You Associate with Your Profile: We collect and/or access information that you associate with your profile, which includes your contact information, financial account information, and profile picture (if available).

    * (g) Mobile Information: We collect and/or use information from your device when you access our service through the _Zelle_ mobile app (e.g. your contacts, your unique device identifier, your device's operating system, and/or the mobile carrier for your phone). For security purposes, the _Zelle_ mobile app uses third party software to scan your device to detect malware. This scan is performed to protect your account from misuse. We do not collect or store scanned data.

    * (h) Technical Usage Information: We use tracking technologies such as cookies and other similar technologies to measure your usage of the Site.

    * (i) Geolocation Information: When you use the _Zelle_ mobile app, we collect and use your geolocation for security and fraud detection purposes.

See Section 2 for more information.

  * How We Use Your Information 

We use information collected or accessed from you and about you for the following reasons:

(a) to operate our Site;

(b) to provide, improve, and develop our products and services; and

(c) to prevent, detect, investigate, and report fraud and prohibited or illegal activities.

See Section 3 for more information.

  * Who We Share Your Information With

We may share information collected or accessed from you and about you with:

(a) other Users of _Zelle_ with whom you interact;

(b) Early Warning Services, LLC and the rest of our corporate family;

(c) our Network Financial Institutions;

(d) our service providers and other trusted third parties;

(e) other entities with your consent;

(f) law enforcement, government agencies, and other authorized third parties;

(g) others if there is a change of control (change in ownership);

(h) companies in the mobile app industry (mobile carriers, operating systems and platforms); and

(i) ad networks.

Any third party with whom we share your personal information will be legally and/or contractually required to provide the same or equal protection to your personal information as we outline in this Privacy Policy.

See Section 4 for more information.

  * Your Choices

You can control how and when you want to receive notifications from _Zelle_ by updating your preferences in the _Zelle_ mobile app or by following instructions within the notices you receive from us (e.g. using the unsubscribe link in the email you receive from us).

You may request to cancel your profile and enrollment with _Zelle_ by speaking to a customer service representative at 844.428.8542 (8am to midnight EST, excluding federal holidays). However, doing so will immediately terminate your ability to use the service.

See Section 5 for more information.

  * Accessing, Reviewing and Updating Personal Information

You can access, review, and update your personal information by accessing your profile in the _Zelle_ mobile app.

See Section 6 for more information.

  * Our Data Retention Practices

We generally retain information for as long as it is necessary and relevant for our operations and to comply with applicable law.

You may request to cancel your profile and enrollment with _Zelle_ by speaking to a customer service representative at 844-428-8542 (8am to midnight EST). Information from closed or suspended profiles will only be retained as necessary to comply with law, prevent fraud, prevent re-registration, assist with investigations, resolve disputes, analyze or troubleshoot programs, enforce our terms and conditions, or take other actions permitted by law.

See Section 7 for more information.

  * How We Use Cookies and Tracking Technologies

We use tracking technologies (including cookies) to recognize you, protect your privacy, and customize your experience on the Site.

See Section 8 for more information.

  * Notice to California Residents 

If you are a California resident, you may request information about our practices related to disclosing your personal information and how we respond to Do Not Track signals.

See Section 9 for more information.

  * Links to Third-Parties

We are not responsible for the privacy practices of third-party websites that are linked to or from our website. Please refer to the privacy notices of those websites for information regarding their privacy practices.

See Section 10 for more information.

  * Security

To help us protect the privacy of your data, we maintain technical, physical, and administrative security measures to protect against loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, or alteration. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls, data encryption, physical access controls to our data centers and information access authorization controls.

See Section 11 for more information.

  * Children's Privacy

The User Service Agreement defines eligibility requirements to use the _Zelle_ mobile app. Our Site is not intended for children under the age of 13. **For information about the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), visit the FTC website:[www.ftc.gov](https://www.ftc.gov/).**

See Section 12 for more information.

  * Territorial Scope and Processing

We are located in the United States. Our services are available for eligible United States users only. Our operations use a network of computers, cloud-based services, and other infrastructure and information technology that are based in the United States. Additionally, we may use third-party service providers that may be located in and process or store your personal information in the United States, the European Union, and other countries. If you create a profile, you consent to the collection and/or processing of your personal information and tracking technologies/cookies as described in this Privacy Policy.

See Section 13 for more information.

  * Notification Regarding Updates to This Privacy Policy

You agree that we may notify you about material changes to this Privacy Policy by posting notices on this Site.

See Section 14 for more information.

  * Contact Us

Privacy issues are handled by our Privacy Office. For more information about our privacy practices, please continue to our full Privacy Policy below or send an email to [privacyoffice@earlywarning.com](mailto:privacyoffice@earlywarning.com).

See Section 15 for more information.

### _Full Privacy Policy_

**1\. Scope and Consent**

When you use the Site, you are contracting with Early Warning Services, LLC, located at 16552 N. 90th Street, Scottsdale, AZ 85260. By using the Site, you expressly consent to our collection, use, disclosure, and retention of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.

Your use of the website and/or _Zelle_ mobile app is also governed by the Service Agreement [User Service Agreement](https://zellepay.com/user-service-agreement), the [Just in Time Notice](https://zellepay.com/just-time-notice), and [Terms of Use](https://zellepay.com/terms-use). Do not use the Site if you do not agree to these terms.

**2\. Information We Collect or Access About You**

We collect or access information from you and about you when you use the Site, including:

  1. **Enrollment and Profile Information:** When you enroll as a User or update your information in the _Zelle_ mobile app, we collect personal information from you, such as your name, postal address, email addresses, mobile numbers, your photograph for your User profile (if available), name of the financial institution where you hold accounts and financial account numbers.

Your Network Financial Institution may require you to link your _Zelle_ profile to your financial account. In doing so, we will access and display information about each of the financial accounts you hold at that Network Financial Institution that is eligible for use with the _Zelle_ service (as determined by the Network Financial Institution), including the account balance for each of those accounts, and your email address(es) on file with the Network Financial Institution.

If you are an enrolled User and have a financial account at one of our Network Financial Institutions, we may also collect personal information from that Network Financial Institution if it receives a notification that your financial account information in our database is inaccurate and needs to be changed. Additionally, if you are an enrolled User and have a financial account at one of our Network Financial Institutions, your bank's privacy policy may also apply to the information that we collect through our Site and to the information that your bank provides to us.

In addition, we may collect personal information from third party services in order to process your registration, verify your identity, verify your financial account information, and protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud or unauthorized use.

  2. **Information About Your Transactions:** When you use the _Zelle_ mobile app to send or request money, we collect information such as when and where the transaction occurs, the names of the transacting parties, the mobile phone numbers or email addresses of the transacting parties, a description of the transactions (including text you put in the memo field), the transaction amount, and the devices and payment methods used to complete the transactions.
  3. **Information to Respond to Your Requests:** You may give us your personal information when you contact us for assistance and to sign up for our newsletters and for other communications. See the section titled "Your Choices" for information on how you can opt-out of receiving communications from us.
  4. **Information about Your Friends and Family that You Invite to Join _Zelle_ :** If you invite your friends and family to join _Zelle_ or you initiate a money transfer to or from them, you may give us their personal information so we can invite them to use _Zelle_. You should receive their consent to share their personal information with us before submitting it to us. You should also tell your friends and family that the notification will come from _Zelle_ by email or text (whichever communication method you provide to us) and that the payment notice or request will include your name.
  5. **Information from Other Sources:** The information we collect may be combined with information from outside records (e.g., demographic information, additional contact information) that we have acquired in accordance with the law.
  6. **Content You Associate With Your Profile:** We collect or access any information you enter into your User profile. This includes your contact information, your financial account information, your profile photograph (if you upload one) and any other information that you associate with your profile.
  7. **Mobile Information:** When you access the service through the _Zelle_ mobile app, we may collect or use information from your mobile device such as: 
    1. your unique device identifier;
    2. location or GPS/geo-location;
    3. Wi-Fi base identifier (BSSID);
    4. mobile phone number;
    5. mobile device name;
    6. contacts and photos paired with your contacts (we access, but do not store, contact information to facilitate your transaction);
    7. apps downloaded or used;
    8. biometric verification information (e.g., fingerprint or facial recognition) (we access, but do not store, this information when you use this method of authentication on your mobile phone);
    9. passwords (e.g., passwords you create to access the mobile app, and those that may be associated with your banking credentials with your permission (see Section 2a for more information)); and
    10. for security purposes, the _Zelle_ mobile app also uses third party software to scan your device to detect malware (this scan is performed to protect your account from misuse, we do not collect or store scanned data).
  8. **Technical Usage Information:** When you visit our Site, we collect usage information sent to us by your computer, mobile phone, or other access device which may include your browser type and language; country and language setting on your device; Internet Protocol (“IP”) address; the domain name of your Internet Service Provider, mobile device and operating system; screens you visit in the mobile app; content you view on the website; features you use; the date and time of your visit to or use of the Site; the website you visited before you visited our website; and data about how you interact with our Site. During some visits, we may use software tools to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, time spent on certain pages and page interaction information. To learn more about how we use tracking technologies and cookies, see Section 8 of this Privacy Policy and our Cookies and Tracking Technologies Policy.
  9. **Geolocation Information:** When you use the _Zelle_ mobile app, we may collect and use geo-location information for security and fraud detection purposes.

Our goal is to collect only that information that we believe is required for our legitimate business interests, to operate the Site, to authenticate and verify your identity, to prevent fraud, and to improve your experience of using the Site.

3\. **How We Use Your Information**

Data collected or accessed will only be used for the purposes specified in the Privacy Policy. If the data will be used for other purposes, we will notify you of those additional purposes, and obtain your consent where necessary. We may use the data we collect for a number of purposes, including:

  1. **_To Operate Our Site:  _** We use information we collect or access about you to: 
    1. respond to your requests and to comply with your stated communication preferences;
    2. enable our Network Financial Institutions to complete money transfers between their customers and you;
    3. enable registered Users to send you money or request money from you (see Section 4(a) for additional information);
    4. notify you, by text or email, of a pending money transfer or request for payment;
    5. verify changes you have made to your personal information;
    6. facilitate your enrollment in the _Zelle_ mobile app as a User and to resolve issues relating to your enrollment;
    7. research and resolve issues related to a transaction you sent or received;
    8. verify the existence of your financial account;
    9. verify your identity;
    10. provide customer service and obtain your feedback regarding the Site (e.g., to resolve disputes, problems with your User profile or the Site);
    11. to enforce our terms and conditions;
    12. to provide other services you request;
    13. guide decisions and improve the Site, including using Site analytics;
    14. to maintain or give you information about your _Zelle_ profile;
    15. create and deliver targeted marketing and advertising tracked to what we believe may potentially interest you;
    16. provide you with a safe, efficient, and customized experience; and
    17. contact you or perform other duties as authorized by law.
  2. **_To Provide and Improve Our Services_** : We use information we collect or access about you to help us create, develop, operate, deliver, and improve our products and services.
  3. **_To Prevent Fraud and Prohibited or Illegal Activities_** : We use information we collect or access about you to prevent, detect, investigate, and report fraud, security breaches, potentially prohibited or illegal activities, or otherwise to protect our services or Users. Information may also be used to respond to subpoenas or other legal processes, as permitted by law.

4\. **Who We Share Your Information With**

To provide you with the service, and as described in Section 3 of this Privacy Policy, we need to share some information about you with others. Information collected or accessed on the Site may be shared with entities both within and outside of our corporate family. Please note that any third party with whom we share your personal information will be legally and/or contractually required to provide the same or equal protection to your personal data as we outline in this Privacy Policy. We may share your information with the following entities:

  1. **_Other Users of _Zelle_ with Whom You Interact:_** We may share information about you with other Users of _Zelle_ with whom you interact through _Zelle_. For example, when another User sends you a payment, we may share your first name (from your _Zelle_ profile) with the other User to ensure the other User intends to send a payment to you. We do not share your financial account information with other _Zelle_ Users.
  2. **_The Early Warning Services, LLC Corporate Family:_** We may share information about you with the Early Warning Services, LLC corporate family, including our subsidiaries.
  3. **_Our Network Financial Institutions:_ ** We may share your personal information with Network Financial Institutions and affiliates.
  4. **_Our Service Providers and Other Third-Parties:_** We may share your information with our service providers and other trusted third parties such as customer support service centers, advertising networks, analytics tools providers, and software development kit providers we hire to help with our business operations (including, but not limited to, providing customer service, verifying your identity, preventing and detecting fraudulent activity, analytics, marketing as permissible, operations, and enforcing of our terms and conditions).
  5. **_Other Entities with Your Consent:_** We may share your personal information with other third-parties to whom you explicitly ask us to send your information (or about whom you are otherwise explicitly notified and consent to when using a specific service). On the Site, you may have opportunities to express interest in or register for other services. If you do, we will provide information about you to those third-parties, or parties working on their behalf, to facilitate your request.
  6. **_Law Enforcement, Government Agencies and Other Authorized Third Parties:_** We may share information about you, as permitted by law, with law enforcement, governmental agencies, and other authorized third-parties.
  7. **_Change of Control - New Owners:_** We may share your information with other business entities, should we plan to merge with or be acquired by that business entity. Should this occur, we will make reasonable efforts to request that the new combined entity follow this Privacy Policy with respect to your personal information. If your personal information would be used contrary to this Privacy Policy, we will request that the new owner provide you with prior notice.
  8. **_Companies in the Mobile App Industry:_** When you access the _Zelle_ mobile app through a mobile device, we may share your information with mobile carriers, operating systems and platforms.
  9. **_Ad Networks:_** On our website, we may allow third parties to provide analytics services and serve _Zelle_ advertisements on our behalf. These entities may use their own cookies, web beacons, device identifiers, and other technologies to collect information about your use of the website, including your IP address, web browser, internet service provider information, the website you came from, pages viewed, time spent on pages or in apps, links clicked, and conversion information. This information may be used by us and others to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, and deliver Zelle advertising on our website and other websites. The use of these technologies by these third parties is subject to their own privacy policies and is not covered by this Privacy Policy. For more information about third party ad servers at our Site and your ability to opt-out of targeted advertising from such third parties, please visit [Ad Choices](http://optout.aboutads.info/) and our Cookies and Tracking Technologies Policy.

**5\. Your Choices**

You can control how and when you want to receive notifications from us by following instructions within the notices you receive from us and by updating your preferences in the _Zelle_ mobile app.

To opt out of marketing communications from us, use the options in the communications we send, send an email request to [requestoptout@earlywarning.com](mailto:requestoptout@earlywarning.com), and/or visit [Ad Choices](http://optout.aboutads.info/) (for targeted marketing) as per Section 4(i) above.

You may not opt-out of administrative emails (for example, emails about your transactions or policy changes) for your enrolled profile.

You may request to cancel your profile and enrollment with _Zelle_ by speaking to a customer service representative at 844-428-8542 (8am to midnight EST, excluding federal holidays). However, doing so will immediately terminate your ability to use the service.

**6\. Accessing, Reviewing, and Updating Your Personal Information**

You can access, review and update your personal information at any time by accessing your profile in the _Zelle_ mobile app. You can update your User profile and registration information, including your financial account, personal information and email addresses/mobile numbers. Keeping this information up-to-date is very important. If this information is incomplete, inaccurate or not current, please update your information by looking into your profile.

**7\. Our Data Retention Practices**

We generally retain information for as long as it is necessary and relevant for our operations and to comply with applicable law.

You may request to cancel your profile and enrollment with _Zelle_ by speaking to a customer service representative at 844-428-8542 (8am to midnight EST). Information from closed or suspended profiles will only be retained as necessary to comply with law, prevent fraud, prevent re-registration, assist with investigations, resolve disputes, analyze or troubleshoot programs, enforce our terms and conditions, or take other actions permitted by law.

8\. **How We Use Cookies and Tracking Technologies**

When you visit the Site, you consent to the use of cookies and tracking technologies as well as the corresponding processing of your personal information. We and our third parties may use cookies and other tracking technologies for a variety of purposes, as outlined in this Privacy Policy and as described below. You can withdraw your consent at any time by deleting placed cookies and disabling cookies in your browser. For further information about our use of cookies and tracking technologies and your opt-out choices, see Your Cookie Choices & How to Opt-Out (<https://www.zellepay.com/legal-cookies-and-tracking-technology#YourCookieChoices>).

  1. **Operationally Necessary.** We may use tracking technologies required for system administration, to prevent fraudulent activity and improve security. We are not required to obtain your consent for tracking technologies that are operationally necessary.
  2. **Performance-Related.** We may use cookies or other tracking technologies to assess the performance of the online services, including as part of our analytic practices to improve the content offered through the online services.
  3. **Functionality-Related.** We may use tracking technologies to tell us, for example, whether you have visited the website before or if you are a new visitor and to help us identify the features in which you may have the greatest interest.
  4. **Targeting-Related.** We may use tracking technologies to deliver content, including ads, relevant to your interests on our online service and third-party sites based on how you interact with our advertisements or content as well as track the content you access (including video viewing). Further information on this, and your opt-out choices are described at here.

During some visits we may use software tools to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, time spent on certain pages and page interaction information.

A few additional important things you should know about our use of tracking technologies (e.g., cookies, HTML-5 stored technologies):

  * We offer certain features that are available only through the use of tracking technologies.
  * We use both persistent and temporary tracking technologies. Tracking technologies (e.g., cookies) can either be persistent (i.e., they remain on your computer until you delete them) or temporary (i.e., they last only until you close your browser). You are always free to decline tracking technologies if your browser permits, although doing so may interfere with your use of the Site. Refer to the help section of your browser, browser extensions, or installed applications for instructions on blocking, deleting, or disabling tracking technologies such as cookies.
  * We use cookies and tracking technologies with your prior consent as obtained through your use of this Site.
  * You may encounter tracking technologies/cookies from our third-party service providers that we have allowed on our Site that assist us with various aspects of our Site operations and services, such as Google Analytics.
  * To learn more about limiting the collection of tracking technology/cookie data, visit [Ad Choices](http://optout.aboutads.info/).

For more information about the use of cookies and similar technology on our Site, please review Sections 2 and 3  of this Privacy Policy and our Cookies and Tracking Technologies Policy.

9\. **Notice to California Residents**

  1. **How California Residents Can Request a List of Third Parties that Received Personal Information:** California residents may request a list of all third-parties to which our Site has disclosed certain personal information (as defined by California law) during the preceding year for those third-parties' direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and want such a list, please contact us at [privacyoffice@earlywarning.com](mailto:privacyoffice@earlywarning.com). For all requests, you must put the statement "Your California Privacy Rights" in the body of your request, as well as your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. In the body of your request, please provide enough information for us to determine if this applies to you. You need to attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for our response. Please note that we will not accept requests via the telephone, mail, or by facsimile, and we are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or that do not have complete information.
  2. **How We Respond to Do Not Track Signals for California Residents:** California Business & Professions Code Section 22575(b) (as amended effective January 1, 2014) provides that California residents are entitled to know how we respond to "Do Not Track" browser settings. We do not currently take actions to respond to Do Not Track signals because a uniform technological standard has not yet been developed. We continue to review new technologies and may adopt a standard once one is created.

**10\. Links to Third-Parties**

Our website may contain links to other third-party websites, such as our Network Financial Institutions. When you leave our website and visit those websites, you are bound by the privacy policies of those websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of these third party websites, which are governed by their own privacy policies and practices.

11\. **Security**

To help us protect the privacy of your data, we maintain technical, physical, and administrative security measures to protect against loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, or alteration. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls, data encryption, physical access controls to our data centers and information access authorization controls. It is your responsibility to make sure that your personal information is accurate and that your password(s) and profile registration information are secure and not shared with third-parties. Additionally, we use security features that are built into the hardware and software of your device to help protect your transactions, such as facial or fingerprint recognition. We do not collect or store your biometric verification information.

12\. **Children's Privacy**

The User Service Agreement defines eligibility requirements to use the Zelle mobile app. Our Site is not intended for children under the age of 13. **For information about the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), visit the FTC website:[www.ftc.gov](https://www.ftc.gov/)**.

13\. **Territorial Scope and Processing**

We are located in the United States. Our services are available for eligible United States users only. Our operations use a network of computers, cloud-based services, and other infrastructure and information technology that are based in the United States. Additionally, we may use third-party service providers that may be located in and process or store your personal information in the United States, the European Union, and other countries. If you create a profile, you consent to the collection and/or processing of your personal information and tracking technologies/cookies as described in this Privacy Policy.

14\. **Notification Regarding Updates to This Privacy Policy**

From time to time, we may update this Privacy Policy. You agree that we may notify you about material changes in the way we treat personal information by placing a notice on the Site. You should check the Site frequently for updates.

15\. **Contact Us**

If your questions are not answered in this Privacy Policy, you may email us at [privacyoffice@earlywarning.com](mailto:privacyoffice@earlywarning.com), or write to us at Early Warning Services, LLC., Attn: Privacy Office, 16552 N. 90th St, Scottsdale, AZ 85260.
